Another grueling day.
I just wanna go home
and do nothing.
K-Koichi…
Hazamada…
Hey, what's new?
Th-Thanks again for the other day.
Um, are you all better now?
Sorta, I guess.
They sent me home two days ago.
Where's that bastard—
I mean, where's Josuke?
He already went home.
Supposedly he found an
invisible baby yesterday,
and there was this big
to-do over finding its mother.
So it's a Stand user?
It would seem.
Apparently, the baby bonded
with Josuke's dad, Mr. Joestar.
In fact, without Mr. Joestar close by,
she turns everything around her invisible.
So is Mr. Joestar gonna stick
around here for a while, then?
Seems likely.
I see.
Hey, Koichi, ya like manga?
Manga?
I guess I like comics
as much as the next guy.
Ever heard of Rohan Kishibe,
the guy who draws Pink Dark Boy?
Pink Dark Boy? Of course!
I'm a huge fan!
Really? You like it?
The suspense-horror series, right?
It can get pretty gross,
but that spine-tingling
sense of looming dread…
and those super realistic characters…
aren't they great?
Yeah, yeah!
Did you know Rohan Kishibe
lives right here in Morioh?
Huh?!
What?! He lives in Morioh?!
No way!
You can't be serious! Really?!
I couldn't believe it, either!
I overheard some realtors talking.
It's mind-boggling,
I know, but it's true!
MORIOH STATION
ROHAN KISHIBE'S HOUSE
Hell yeah! I'm there!
You and I, we really get each other.
Really?
KISHIBE
There!
I think that might be his studio.
The light's on!
You're right…
I wonder if he has any family.
I heard he lives alone.
He made his debut at sixteen,
and now he's twenty.
Twenty?! He's so young!
So he was about
my age when he went pro…
KISHIBE
It's no use snooping around, Koichi.
Just ring the doorbell.
M-Me?
Do it! I have seniority over you!
This kind of stuff makes me nervous.
What? That's not fair…
EPISODE 14
LET'S GO TO
THE MANGA ARTIST'S HOUSE, PART 1
That face!
Rohan Kishibe!
He looks exactly like his picture
on the cover of that
special New Year's edition!
Uh, I mean… Rohan-sensei!
H-Huh?
And who, pray tell, are you two?
What are you up to?
Some kind of prank?
N-No! We would never!
Um, we go to
Budogaoka High School.
W-We're your fans, Sensei.
Fans? Of me?
You've read my stuff?
So somebody leaked my address…
N-No, um…
I just happened to hear…
Pardon our rudeness,
but nothing would make us
happier than your autograph.
So you're fans, huh?
Tremendous.
We just might be
on the same wavelength, then.
Huh?
Nothing, never mind. Pardon me.
An autograph or two
will be no trouble at all.
Yes! Aren't you glad we came?
I know.
While you're here, I could
give you a studio tour if you'd like.
Huh?
We can see where you work?!
My work is done for the day.
If you two are interested…
Yes!
Then…
'Souse us!
Please.
Wow!
Wow! A four-color manuscript!
Incredible!
It's so much more powerful in person!
I-I'm overwhelmed!
Thank god we came!
How long have you
been practicing your craft in Morioh?
I moved here three months ago.
My family's home is in S City,
but I used to live here
when I was a child.
Tokyo has its perks,
but it's too chaotic for me.
It has none of Morioh's serenity,
and is entirely unconducive to creativity.
Besides,
with today's advanced
fax machines and photocopiers,
I can send a complete
manuscript in four hours.
You could say there's no point
in living in the city now,
other than for the pettiness of status.
Um… And what do you do
about assistants and staff?
I have none.
I draw everything myself.
Huh? You do everything solo?!
You draw 19 pages of those
intricate drawings in one week?!
- I can do it in four.
- What?!
Five if they're in color.
On the other days,
I amuse myself with travel and such.
I'm not much of a people person,
which is why I chose
to be a manga artist.
An assistant would be
a worry and a hindrance.
That's so amazing… Wow.
You're a genius!
Excuse me.
Whoa, a s-spider!
Suburbia never ceases to amaze.
The bugs and spiders are everywhere.
Um… Sensei?
I see… So this spider is
an Araneus ventricosus…
The species inhabits homes
and rural areas across Japan.
It's primarily an orb-weaving spider,
and some weave webs day and night.
By the way, you two,
do you know what it takes
to create captivating manga?
Reality!
Reality is the force
that makes a drawing come alive.
Reality is entertainment.
People assume manga is
born of imagination and fantasy,
but nothing could
be further from the truth!
For me, it is capturing the seen,
the experienced, the felt,
that makes for great manga!
Take this spider…
Something a typical city-dweller
would simply kill in disgust.
The way the legs connect
to the body, the position of its eyes,
the differences
between male and female.
A manga artist must understand
these elements to draw a spider.
It's said a spider's silk
solidifies when exposed to air,
but what about its spinnerets?
And then, there's the arrangement
of its internal organs.
How does a spider
whose belly has been sliced open
squirm in agony
while in the throes of death?
To depict reality,
one must know such things.
That's barbaric!
Barbaric?!
An amateur punk like you is
telling me, Rohan Kishibe, his opinion?!
N-No! I wasn't voicing my opinion!
I'm sorry!
Now for a taste.
The stereotype is true.
Manga artists really are total weirdos!
Very nice!
An excellent expression of agony…
A perfect example
of the vomiting reflex!
I must sketch it.
R-Really?
Now you're pretending.
Forget it. No sketch.
It won't be of any use.
I-I'm sorry.
Autographs, correct?
I'll go get a pen from the kitchen.
I'll bring out some tea, as well.
Oh, you don't have to…
That was amazing! I had no idea…
That need to know every little detail
must be what makes
Pink Dark Boy so amazing.
Um, Hazamada…
I know we just got here, but, um…
Maybe, shouldn't we get going?
Huh? Get going?
You want to go home? Why?
Aren't you having fun?
I can't really say why, but…
It's just a feeling.
My gut has been
known to be wrong…
I just got the feeling there's something
dangerous about Rohan-sensei.
Dangerous?
You mean
he might be a Stand user?
No! Nothing like that. Just, um…
Just because Rohan-Sensei's
kind of off-the-wall,
doesn't mean you should jump to
the conclusion that he's a Stand user.
I'm not jumping to any conclusion…
I just have a bad feeling.
Besides, if Rohan-sensei
really is a Stand user,
wouldn't that be great for us?
We'd have something in common
with a famous manga artist.
But, I feel you.
If something's making you
feel weird,
then that means it's time to go home.
We can always come back.
But!
Only after I've looked at this thing
that caught my eye.
Thing? What thing?
Jeez, Koichi, could you
be any more dense?
On top of the desk,
next to the phone.
Look carefully.
Oh! C-Could this be…
Better believe it!
He said he just
finished working, right?
I've been eyeing that carefully.
A freshly drawn, brand-spanking
new manuscript for Pink Dark Boy?!
Does that mean
no one else has laid eyes on it?!
We'll go home
as soon as I get a glimpse of this.
We have to get Sensei's permission!
Koichi, you really don't know anything
about manga artists, do you?
These pre-printed manuscripts
are highly confidential and top secret!
There's no way
he'd let outsiders like us
look at a manuscript
before the editor!
We'll take a peak,
then put it right back.
All the more reason!
It's fine!
It's not gonna cause any harm.
Huh?
This feeling!
I know it's a thrilling manga,
but seeing it in person like this…
It's giving me goosebumps!
It's so good!
Hurry up and turn the page,
Hazamada.
I'm getting emotional!
It appears…
my manuscript was compatible
with you two, after all.
I thought you would read it.
Only compatible first-time
readers of my manuscript…
H-Hazamada…
K-Koichi…
…will experience with
my Heaven's Door ability,
the very doors to their souls opening!
A-Ability?!
My hand!
K-Koichi! What's going on?!
MORIOH LANDMARK 5
MANGA ARTIST ROHAN KISHIBE'S HOUSE
ONE MINUTE WALK FROM
MORIOH KOTODAI 2-CHOME BUS STOP.
AN APPROXIMATELY 3,665 SQUARE-FOOT,
SEVEN ROOM MANSION WITH AN ATTIC.
IF YOU VISIT,
HE'LL PRETEND TO BE OUT.
Many things are recorded
in the human body.
Everything from the moment
you were born.
To read your records,
I shall transform you both into books.
Books that chronicle your life stories.
- Help!
- You read the manga too, didn't you?
- It's happening to me, too!
- Hazamada!
This will cause you no physical harm,
so there's no need to worry.
Wh-What do you want from us?!
In manga, the creator's
sense of reality is critical, remember?
That is, I will read your lives
and experiences,
and you will flood
my consciousness with realistic ideas.
An interview cannot do the same!
You will tell me everything
with 100% realism,
as if I had experienced it myself.
Koichi Hirose.
Born March 28th, 1984, at 6:27 AM
at Red Cross Hospital in S City.
You were born premature at 2325 grams,
and spent a week in an incubator.
You come from a family of four,
and your older sister's name is Ayana…
I see…
In grade school and middle school
you led a relatively ordinary life,
you also happen to
be remarkably genuine.
Admirable indeed.
You…
And what is this ability?! Reverb?
So I am not alone in having
this kind of ability?!
You, too?
So Stand users… This is…
Everything after
April, 1999 is astonishing!
I see a sudden
explosion of amazing experiences!
Josuke Higashikata, Jotaro Kujo,
Yukako Yamagishi, Okuyasu
Nijimura, Tamami Kobayashi…
It's unbelievable…
It's incredible! It's captivating!
I just uncovered the motherlode
of manga material, Koichi Hirose!
Shining Diamond,
Star Platinum,
The Hand, Love Deluxe,
et cetera, et cetera!
Wh-What are you gonna do with us?!
I'm taking your memories
to use in my own manga!
Reverb!
I'm asking you to stop attacking us
with your Stand this instant!
Otherwise…
You'll attack me with
Reverb Act 2's sound?
Yes! Release me from your Stand!
I won't hold back!
I know. It's written on page eleven.
You're far more timid than most,
and many tend to disrespect you,
but when push comes to shove,
you have the courage
to conquer your fears.
Truly magnificent!
I like you!
I'm sure my readers
will like you, too.
I'm not bluffing!
I will attack you!
Oh, be quiet…
Try me!
Reverb Act 2!
CRASH
Huh? I-I missed?!
I'm not sure you missed.
You sure it wasn't on purpose?
Your control is way off!
Then how about this?!
CRASH
Where are you attacking?!
Koichi, unfortunately for you,
I placed a safety lock on Reverb.
Huh?
You are no longer able to attack me.
Safety lock?
Look… I've already written it into
the margin of page eleven, here.
I CANNOT ATTACK
MANGA ARTIST, ROHAN KISHIBE
MANGA ARTIST, ROHAN KISHIBE.
CANNOT
Behold, the power of Heaven's Door.
Through it, I can read people's
experiences via words and pictures.
Conversely, I can write in new memories.
No matter what you try,
you'll never be able to do me
any harm now.
Wh-What?!
But that's it. No more tampering.
Any more, and your life
will lose all authenticity.
It's of no benefit to my work.
Now let's see…
Let's have a look at Hazamada.
Sensei! You are a genius!
I respect you!
Huh… I see.
Let's see…
You sometimes find comfort in
picking on the weak,
like kittens and small birds.
You want to have your way
with Junko, a junior from class E,
but you're too cowardly
to act on that desire.
Your testicles often grow sweaty,
and when you adjust them
during class,
nothing thrills you more than
the thought that someone might see you.
You're an appalling excuse of a man.
Including such a character
into my manga would turn off readers.
I can't use you.
This is too much!
- Why?
- There's no hope for me!
Why are you doing this?
You don't need my experiences.
You're amazing manga artist
on your own!
The world knows that!
You're only twenty years old,
and you live in this amazing house!
Think of how blessed you are compared
with most people your age!
So why do you need my memories?!
Do you think that I,
Rohan Kishibe, draw manga
to garner money and admiration?!
I draw manga so
that people will read it!
To be read is my only motive!
It's only a single, simple reason,
but it's all I care about!
So people read my work,
I search for realism every single day!
Listen. Finishing a manuscript
always makes me feel good.
Everyone feels good after
finishing work, don't they?
But that gratification is fleeting.
That's because,
I begin to think
no one will read my manga,
and my insecurities are awakened.
Maybe next week
there will be no readers, I think…
Maybe I won't know
what to draw anymore.
Maybe I'll lose all motivation.
These recurring thoughts
have tormented me
over and over since I was sixteen.
Until three months ago,
when someone shot me with an arrow,
and I gained the ability of Heaven's Door.
Keicho Nijimura…
Yes, that was also written in you.
I'm sure you two have no idea
what it's like to find
the perfect inspiration
for a masterpiece!
But this is it!
There's nothing better!
Koichi, I'm going to make
your reality mine!
See, Koichi?
Wasn't Rohan-sensei a nice guy?
Aren't you glad we went?
It really was fun!
TO HIROSE
ROHAN KISHIBE
Not only did he give us
these great autographs,
he even served us tea and cookies.
I wanna go back.
Yeah. Let's go again.
Well, I'm heading this way, so…
He really was a great guy.
You'll never speak of this, Koichi.
Huh?!
Wh-Why?!
How did I lose 20 kilograms?
But I look exactly the same!
It reads five kilograms…
The scale's not broken.
Th-This is crazy!
Th-This has to be the work
of an enemy Stand!
There's no other way
I'd lose 20 kilograms!
But who…
I have to talk to Josuke about this.
Ko, what are you doing?
Huh?
Me? U-Uh…
Wait… What was it?
What are you talking about?
Weirdo.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing. My little brother's
wandering around in his underwear.
What was it?
I could've sworn I was thinking about
something really important just now.
Well, if I forgot that easily,
it couldn't have been that important.
Boy, my shoes and bag
sure feel heavy today.
Huh?
Th-This house…
Why?
Somehow I ended up
walking to Rohan-Sensei's house.
The door's open…
I'd like to drop in
and thank him for yesterday,
but I'll be late for school.
I probably shouldn't.
Being a manga artist,
he'll probably still be asleep.
I really shouldn't just barge in.
This really isn't such a good idea…
Hey, did you see that, Okuyasu?
Yeah…
We followed Koichi because
he was heading in
the opposite direction of the school,
but what the heck is he doing?
Whose house is that?
There's no way but,
you don't think it's some chick, do ya?
Rohan-sensei..
He's working with
such a chilling expression.
What is this…
I can't shake the feeling that
being here is actually terrifying.
What is it?
So you made it.
I've been waiting.
You're right on time.
EPISODE 15
LET'S GO TO
THE MANGA ARTIST'S HOUSE, PART 2